[
  {
    "question": "1. Which tasks can be accomplished by using the command history feature? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Set the command history buffer size."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Recall previously entered commands."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What is the first action in the boot sequence when a switch is powered on?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "load a power-on self-test program"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. What must an administrator have in order to reset a lost password on a router?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "physical access to the router"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. When configuring a switch for SSH access, what other command that is associated with the login local command is required to be entered on the switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "username username secret secret"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. Which command displays information about the auto-MDIX setting for a specific interface?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "show controllers"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. If one end of an Ethernet connection is configured for full duplex and the other end of the connection is configured for half duplex, where would late collisions be observed?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "on the half-duplex end of the connection"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. Which command is used to set the BOOT environment variable that defines where to find the IOS image file on a switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "boot system"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. What does a switch use to locate and load the IOS image?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "BOOT environment variable"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Which protocol adds security to remote connections?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SSH"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. What is a characteristic of an IPv4 loopback interface on a Cisco IOS router?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is a logical interface internal to the router."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "11. What is the minimum Ethernet frame size that will not be discarded by the receiver as a runt frame?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "64 bytes"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "12. After which step of the switch bootup sequence is the boot loader executed?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "after POST execution"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "13. Which impact does adding a Layer 2 switch have on a network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "an increase in the size of the broadcast domain"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "14. Which characteristic describes cut-through switching?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Frames are forwarded without any error checking."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "15. What is the significant difference between a hub and a Layer 2 LAN switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A hub extends a collision domain, and a switch divides collision domains."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "16. Which statement is correct about Ethernet switch frame forwarding decisions?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Frame forwarding decisions are based on MAC address and port mappings in the CAM table."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "17. How do switch buffers affect network performance?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "They store frames received, thus preventing premature frame discarding when network congestion occurs."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "18. Which switch characteristic helps keep traffic local and alleviates network congestion?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "high port density"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "19. Which switch component reduces the amount of packet handling time inside the switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ASIC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "21. What information is added to the switch table from incoming frames?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "source MAC address and incoming port number"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "22. Which switching method ensures that the incoming frame is error-free before forwarding?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "store-and-forward"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "23. Refer to the exhibit. How many broadcast domains are displayed?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "8"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "24. Under which two occasions should an administrator disable DTP while managing a local area network? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "when connecting a Cisco switch to a non-Cisco switch"
      },
      {
        "answer": "on links that should not be trunking"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "25. Which two characteristics describe the native VLAN? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The native VLAN traffic will be untagged across the trunk link."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The native VLAN provides a common identifier to both ends of a trunk."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "26. On a switch that is configured with multiple VLANs, which command will remove only VLAN 100 from the switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Switch(config)# no vlan 100"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "27. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is reviewing port and VLAN assignments on switch S2 and notices that interfaces Gi0/1 and Gi0/2 are not included in the output. Why would the interfaces be missing from the output?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "They are configured as trunk interfaces."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "28. A network contains multiple VLANs spanning multiple switches. What happens when a device in VLAN 20 sends a broadcast Ethernet frame?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Only devices in VLAN 20 see the frame."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "29. Refer to the exhibit. All workstations are configured correctly in VLAN 20. Workstations that are connected to switch SW1 are not able to send traffic to workstations on SW2. What could be done to remedy the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Allow VLAN 20 on the trunk link."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "30. What happens to switch ports after the VLAN to which they are assigned is deleted?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The ports stop communicating with the attached devices."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "32. Refer to the exhibit. In what switch mode should port G0/1 be assigned if Cisco best practices are being used?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "trunk"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "34. Port Fa0/11 on a switch is assigned to VLAN 30. If the command no switchport access vlan 30 is entered on the Fa0/11 interface, what will happen?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Port Fa0/11 will be returned to VLAN 1."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "35. Which command displays the encapsulation type, the voice VLAN ID, and the access mode VLAN for the Fa0/1 interface?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "show interfaces Fa0/1 switchport"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "36. Refer to the exhibit. A technician is programming switch SW3 to manage voice and data traffic through port Fa0/20. What, if anything, is wrong with the configuration?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The command used to assign the voice VLAN to the switch port is incorrect."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "37. Which four steps are needed to configure a voice VLAN on a switch port? (Choose four).",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Assign the voice VLAN to the switch port."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Ensure that voice traffic is trusted and tagged with a CoS priority value."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Add a voice VLAN."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Configure the switch port in access mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "38. Refer to the exhibit. PC1 is unable to communicate with server 1. The network administrator issues the show interfaces trunk command to begin troubleshooting. What conclusion can be made based on the output of this command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Interface G0/2 is not configured as a trunk."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "39. Refer to the exhibit. What is the cause of the error that is displayed in the configuration of inter-VLAN routing on router CiscoVille?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The encapsulation dot1Q 20 command has not been configured.​"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "40. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator has configured router CiscoVille with the above commands to provide inter-VLAN routing. What command will be required on a switch that is connected to the Gi0/0 interface on router CiscoVille to allow inter-VLAN routing?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "switchport mode trunk"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "41. A high school uses VLAN15 for the laboratory network and VLAN30 for the faculty network. What is required to enable communication between these two VLANs while using the router-on-a-stick approach?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A switch with a port that is configured as a trunk is needed when connecting to the router."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "42. When routing a large number of VLANs, what are two disadvantages of using the router-on-a-stick inter-VLAN routing method rather than the multilayer switch inter-VLAN routing method? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A dedicated router is required."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Multiple subinterfaces may impact the traffic flow speed."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "43. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is verifying the configuration of inter-VLAN routing. Users complain that PCs on different VLANs cannot communicate. Based on the output, what are two configuration errors on switch interface Gi1/1? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Gi1/1 is in the default VLAN."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Gi1/1 is configured as trunk mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "44. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is verifying the configuration of inter-VLAN routing. Users complain that PC2 cannot communicate with PC1. Based on the output, what is the possible cause of the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The encapsulation dot1Q 5 command contains the wrong VLAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "45. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator has configured router CiscoVille with the above commands to provide inter-VLAN routing. What type of port will be required on a switch that is connected to Gi0/0 on router CiscoVille to allow inter-VLAN routing?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "trunk port"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "46. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring RT1 for inter-VLAN routing. The switch is configured correctly and is functional. Host1, Host2, and Host3 cannot communicate with each other. Based on the router configuration, what is causing the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "IP addresses on the subinterfaces are incorrectly matched to the VLANs."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "47. Refer to the exhibit. A router-on-a-stick configuration was implemented for VLANs 15, 30, and 45, according to the show running-config command output. PCs on VLAN 45 that are using the 172.16.45.0 /24 network are having trouble connecting to PCs on VLAN 30 in the 172.16.30.0 /24 network. Which error is most likely causing this problem?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "There is an incorrect IP address configured on GigabitEthernet 0/0.30."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "48. What is a characteristic of a routed port on a Layer 3 switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is not assigned to a VLAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "49. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator needs to configure router-on-a-stick for the networks that are shown. How many subinterfaces will have to be created on the router if each VLAN that is shown is to be routed and each VLAN has its own subinterface?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "4"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "50. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw(config-if)# mdix auto command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It automatically adjusts the port to allow device connections to use either a straight-through or a crossover cable."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "51. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw(config-if)# ip address 172.18.33.88 255.255.255.0 command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It applies an IPv4 address to the virtual interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "52. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw# configure terminal command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It enters the global configuration mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "53. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw# configure terminal command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It enters the global configuration mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "54. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw(config-if)# shutdown command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It disables a virtual or physical switch interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "55. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw(config-if)# shutdown command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It disables a virtual or physical switch interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "56. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw(config-if)# ipv6 address 2001:db8:a2b4:88::1/64 command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It applies an IPv6 address to the virtual interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "57. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw(config-if)# exit command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It returns to global configuration mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "58. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw> enable command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It enters privileged mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "58. A technician is configuring a new Cisco 2960 switch. What is the effect of issuing the BranchSw(config-if)# duplex full command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It allows data to flow in both directions at the same time on the interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "60. What type of VLAN should not carry voice and network management traffic?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "data VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "62. What type of VLAN is designed to reserve bandwidth to ensure IP Phone quality?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "voice VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "63. What type of VLAN is initially the management VLAN?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "default VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "64. What type of VLAN is designed to have a delay of less than 150 ms across the network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "voice VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "65. What type of VLAN is used to separate the network into groups of users or devices?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "data VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "66. What type of VLAN is configured specifically for network traffic such as SSH, Telnet, HTTPS, HTTP, and SNMP?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "management VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "68. What type of VLAN supports untagged traffic?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "native VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "69. What type of VLAN supports untagged traffic?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "native VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "70. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator has configured R1 as shown. When the administrator checks the status of the serial interface, the interface is shown as being administratively down. What additional command must be entered on the serial interface of R1 to bring the interface up?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "no shutdown"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "71. Refer to the exhibit. The network administrator wants to configure Switch1 to allow SSH connections and prohibit Telnet connections. How should the network administrator change the displayed configuration to satisfy the requirement?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Modify the transport input command."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "72. Which solution would help a college alleviate network congestion due to collisions?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "a high port density switch"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "73. Which two statements are correct with respect to SVI inter-VLAN routing? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Switching packets is faster with SVI."
      },
      {
        "answer": "There is no need for a connection to a router."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "74. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring inter-VLAN routing on a network. For now, only one VLAN is being used, but more will be added soon. What is the missing parameter that is shown as the highlighted question mark in the graphic?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It identifies the VLAN number."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "75. Which type of VLAN is used to designate which traffic is untagged when crossing a trunk port?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "native"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "76. A network administrator issues the show vlan brief command while troubleshooting a user support ticket. What output will be displayed?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the VLAN assignment and membership for all switch ports"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which message is displayed when 10.10.10.1 is entered into the PC1 Web Browser address bar?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "File Server"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "79. What type of VLAN is configured specifically for network traffic such as SSH, Telnet, HTTPS, HHTP, and SNMP?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "management VLAN"
      },
      {
        "answer": "How to find:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "“Ctrl + F”"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Questions Bank"
      },
      {
        "answer": "NOTE: If you have the new question on this test, please comment Question and Multiple-Choice list in form below this article. We will update answers for you in the shortest time. Thank you! We truly value your contribution to the website."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "1. A DHCP-enabled client PC has just booted. During which two steps will the client PC use broadcast messages when communicating with a DHCP server? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCPDISCOVER"
      },
      {
        "answer": "DHCPREQUEST"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the administrator trying to achieve?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "configuring the router to obtain IP parameters from a DHCPv4 server"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. When a client is requesting an initial address lease from a DHCP server, why is the DHCPREQUEST message sent as a broadcast?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The client may have received offers from multiple servers, and the broadcast serves to implicitly decline those other offers."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Which DHCP IPv4 message contains the following information?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCPDISCOVER"
      },
      {
        "answer": "5. Place the options in the following order:"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. Which protocol automates assignment of IP addresses on a network, and which port number does it use? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCP"
      },
      {
        "answer": "67"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. Refer to the exhibit. PC1 is configured to obtain a dynamic IP address from the DHCP server. PC1 has been shut down for two weeks. When PC1 boots and tries to request an available IP address, which destination IP address will PC1 place in the IP header?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "255.255.255.255"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. Which message does an IPv4 host use to reply when it receives a DHCPOFFER message from a DHCP server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCPREQUEST"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Which command, when issued in the interface configuration mode of a router, enables the interface to acquire an IPv4 address automatically from an ISP, when that link to the ISP is enabled?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip address dhcp"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. Which kind of message is sent by a DHCP client when its IP address lease has expired?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "a DHCPREQUEST unicast message​"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "11. A host PC is attempting to lease an address through DHCP. What message is sent by the server to let the client know it is able to use the provided IP information?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCPACK"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "12. What is one indication that a Windows computer did not receive an IPv4 address from a DHCP server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The computer receives an IP address that starts with 169.254."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "13. Which DHCPv4 message will a client send to accept an IPv4 address that is offered by a DHCP server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "broadcast DHCPREQUEST"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "14. A small coffee shop is offering free Wi-Fi to customers. The network includes a wireless router and a DSL modem that is connected to the local phone company. What method is typically used to configure the connection to the phone company?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Set the WAN connection in the wireless router as a DHCP client."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "15. A company uses DHCP to manage IP address deployment for employee workstations. The IT department deploys multiple DHCP servers in the data center and uses DHCP relay agents to facilitate the DHCP requests from workstations. Which two UDP ports are used to forward DHCP traffic? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "67"
      },
      {
        "answer": "68"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "16. A client device on an Ethernet segment needs an IP address in order to communicate on the network. A DHCP server with IP address 192.168.1.1 has been configured and enabled on the network. How will a client device obtain a usable IP address for this network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Send a DHCPDISCOVER message to physical address FF-FF-FF-FF-FF-FF."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "17. What is an advantage of configuring a Cisco router as a relay agent?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It can provide relay services for multiple UDP services."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "18. Which statement is true about DHCP operation?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "When a device that is configured to use DHCP boots, the client broadcasts a DHCPDISCOVER message to identify any available DHCP servers on the network.​"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "20. A network administrator configures a router to send RA messages with M flag as 0 and O flag as 1. Which statement describes the effect of this configuration when a PC tries to configure its IPv6 address?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It should use the information that is contained in the RA message and contact a DHCPv6 server for additional information."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "21. Refer to the exhibit. What should be done to allow PC-A to receive an IPv6 address from the DHCPv6 server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Add the ipv6 dhcp relay command to interface Fa0/0."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is implementing the stateless DHCPv6 operation for the company. Clients are configuring IPv6 addresses as expected. However, the clients are not getting the DNS server address and the domain name information configured in the DHCP pool. What could be the cause of the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The router is configured for SLAAC operation."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "24. A company uses the SLAAC method to configure IPv6 addresses for the employee workstations. Which address will a client use as its default gateway?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the link-local address of the router interface that is attached to the network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "25. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring a router for DHCPv6 operation. Which conclusion can be drawn based on the commands?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The router is configured for stateless DHCPv6 operation."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "26. A network administrator is analyzing the features that are supported by different first-hop router redundancy protocols. Which statement describes a feature that is associated with HSRP?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "HSRP uses active and standby routers."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "27. Refer to the exhibit. What protocol can be configured on gateway routers R1 and R2 that will allow traffic from the internal LAN to be load balanced across the two gateways to the Internet?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "GLBP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "28. Refer to the exhibit. A network engineer is troubleshooting host connectivity on a LAN that uses a first hop redundancy protocol. Which IPv4 gateway address should be configured on the host?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "192.168.2.100"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "29. Refer to the exhibit. Which destination MAC address is used when frames are sent from the workstation to the default gateway?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "MAC address of the virtual router"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "31. Which FHRP implementation is a Cisco-proprietary protocol that suppports IPv4 load sharing?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "GLBP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "32. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.92.71.0/25. The network administrator reserves 8 IP addresses for servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "118"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "34. After a host has generated an IPv6 address by using the DHCPv6 or SLAAC process, how does the host verify that the address is unique and therefore usable?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The host sends an ICMPv6 neighbor solicitation message to the DHCP or SLAAC-learned address and if no neighbor advertisement is returned, the address is considered unique."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "35. Which statement describes HSRP?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is used within a group of routers for selecting an active device and a standby device to provide gateway services to a LAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the keyword that is displayed on www.netacad.com?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Router"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "43. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 192.168.234.0/27. The network administrator reserves 22 IP addresses for IP phones. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "8"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "44. A company uses DHCP servers to dynamically assign IPv4 addresses to employee workstations. The address lease duration is set as 5 days. An employee returns to the office after an absence of one week. When the employee boots the workstation, it sends a message to obtain an IP address. Which Layer 2 and Layer 3 destination addresses will the message contain?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "FF-FF-FF-FF-FF-FF and 255.255.255.255"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "45. Which command will allow a network administrator to check the IP address that is assigned to a particular MAC address?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Router# show ip dhcp binding"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "46. What is the reason that an ISP commonly assigns a DHCP address to a wireless router in a SOHO environment?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "easy IP address management"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "47. What information can be verified through the show ip dhcp binding command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the IPv4 addresses that are assigned to hosts by the DHCP server"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "48. What is the result of a network technician issuing the command ip dhcp excluded-address 10.0.15.1 10.0.15.15 on a Cisco router?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The Cisco router will exclude 15 IP addresses from being leased to DHCP clients."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "50. Refer to the exhibit. Based on the output that is shown, what kind of IPv6 addressing is being configured?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "stateless DHCPv6"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "51. Which FHRP implementation is a Cisco-proprietary protocol that suppports IPv6 load balancing?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "GLBP for IPv6"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "52. Which set of commands will configure a router as a DHCP server that will assign IPv4 addresses to the 192.168.100.0/23 LAN while reserving the first 10 and the last addresses for static assignment?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.1 192.168.100.10\nip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.101.254\nip dhcp pool LAN-POOL-100\nnetwork 192.168.100.0 255.255.254.0\ndefault-router 192.168.100.1"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "53. What is a result when the DHCP servers are not operational in a network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Workstations are assigned with IP addresses in the 169.254.0.0/16 network."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "54. A company uses the method SLAAC to configure IPv6 addresses for the workstations of the employees. A network administrator configured the IPv6 address on the LAN interface of the router. The interface status is UP. However, the workstations on the LAN segment did not obtain the correct prefix and prefix length. What else should be configured on the router that is attached to the LAN segment for the workstations to obtain the information?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "R1(config)# ipv6 unicast-routing"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "55. Which FHRP implementation is a nonproprietary protocol which relies on ICMP to provide IPv4 redundancy?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "IRDP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "56. Refer to the exhibit. PC-A is unable to receive an IPv6 address from the stateful DHCPv6 server. What is the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The ipv6 dhcp relay command should be applied to interface Gig0/0."
      },
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 dhcp relay"
      },
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 dhcp relay"
      },
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 nd managed-config-flag"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "57. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring a router as a DHCPv6 server. The administrator issues a show ipv6 dhcp pool command to verify the configuration. Which statement explains the reason that the number of active clients is 0?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The state is not maintained by the DHCPv6 server under stateless DHCPv6 operation."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "58. Which FHRP implementation is Cisco-proprietary and permits only one router in a group to forward IPv6 packets?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "HSRP for IPv6"
      },
      {
        "answer": "VRRPv2"
      },
      {
        "answer": "116"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "61. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.3.2.0/24. The network administrator reserves 3 IP addresses for printers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "251"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "62. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 172.23.143.0/26. The network administrator reserves 14 IP addresses for file servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "48"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "63. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.7.30.0/24. The network administrator reserves 5 IP addresses for printers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "249"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "64. Which FHRP implementation is a nonproprietary IPv4-only election protocol with limited scalability?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "VRRPv2"
      },
      {
        "answer": "44"
      },
      {
        "answer": "251"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "67. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.19.44.0/24. The network administrator reserves 6 IP addresses for servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "248"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "68. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 172.21.121.0/25. The network administrator reserves 12 IP addresses for web servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "114"
      },
      {
        "answer": "How to find:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "“Ctrl + F”"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Questions Bank"
      },
      {
        "answer": "NOTE: If you have the new question on this test, please comment Question and Multiple-Choice list in form below this article. We will update answers for you in the shortest time. Thank you! We truly value your contribution to the website."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "1. Which Layer 2 attack will result in legitimate users not getting valid IP addresses?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCP starvation"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What mitigation plan is best for thwarting a DoS attack that is creating a MAC address table overflow?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Enable port security."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Which three Cisco products focus on endpoint security solutions? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Web Security Appliance"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Email Security Appliance"
      },
      {
        "answer": "NAC Appliance"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. True or False?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "In the 802.1X standard, the client attempting to access the network is referred to as the supplicant."
      },
      {
        "answer": "true"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. Which authentication method stores usernames and passwords in the router and is ideal for small networks?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "local AAA"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What represents a best practice concerning discovery protocols such as CDP and LLDP on network devices?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Disable both protocols on all interfaces where they are not required."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. Which protocol should be used to mitigate the vulnerability of using Telnet to remotely manage network devices?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SSH"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. Which statement describes the behavior of a switch when the MAC address table is full?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It treats frames as unknown unicast and floods all incoming frames to all ports within the local VLAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. What device is considered a supplicant during the 802.1X authentication process?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the client that is requesting authentication"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. Refer to the exhibit. Port Fa0/2 has already been configured appropriately. The IP phone and PC work properly. Which switch configuration would be most appropriate for port Fa0/2 if the network administrator has the following goals?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SWA(config-if)# switchport port-security"
      },
      {
        "answer": "SWA(config-if)# switchport port-security maximum 2"
      },
      {
        "answer": "SWA(config-if)# switchport port-security mac-address sticky"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "11. Refer to the exhibit. Port security has been configured on the Fa 0/12 interface of switch S1. What action will occur when PC1 is attached to switch S1 with the applied configuration?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Frames from PC1 will cause the interface to shut down immediately, and a log entry will be made."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "12. Which type of VLAN-hopping attack may be prevented by designating an unused VLAN as the native VLAN?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "VLAN double-tagging"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "13. A network administrator is configuring DAI on a switch with the command ip arp inspection validate src-mac. What is the purpose of this configuration command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It checks the source MAC address in the Ethernet header against the sender MAC address in the ARP body."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "14. Which two commands can be used to enable BPDU guard on a switch? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "S1(config)# spanning-tree portfast bpduguard default"
      },
      {
        "answer": "S1(config-if)# spanning-tree bpduguard enable"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "15. As part of the new security policy, all switches on the network are configured to automatically learn MAC addresses for each port. All running configurations are saved at the start and close of every business day. A severe thunderstorm causes an extended power outage several hours after the close of business. When the switches are brought back online, the dynamically learned MAC addresses are retained. Which port security configuration enabled this?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "sticky secure MAC addresses"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "16. Which type of management frame may regularly be broadcast by an AP?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "beacon"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "17. What are the two methods that are used by a wireless NIC to discover an AP? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "receiving a broadcast beacon frame"
      },
      {
        "answer": "transmitting a probe request"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "18. A technician is configuring the channel on a wireless router to either 1, 6, or 11. What is the purpose of adjusting the channel?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to avoid interference from nearby wireless devices"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "19. While attending a conference, participants are using laptops for network connectivity. When a guest speaker attempts to connect to the network, the laptop fails to display any available wireless networks. The access point must be operating in which mode?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "active"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "20. A network administrator is required to upgrade wireless access to end users in a building. To provide data rates up to 1.3 Gb/s and still be backward compatible with older devices, which wireless standard should be implemented?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "802.11ac"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "21. A technician is about to install and configure a wireless network at a small branch office. What is the first security measure the technician should apply immediately upon powering up the wireless router?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Change the default user-name and password of the wireless router."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "22. On a Cisco 3504 WLC dashboard, which option provides access to the full menu of features?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Advanced"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "23. Which step is required before creating a new WLAN on a Cisco 3500 series WLC?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Create a new VLAN interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "24. A network engineer is troubleshooting a newly deployed wireless network that is using the latest 802.11 standards. When users access high bandwidth services such as streaming video, the wireless network performance is poor. To improve performance the network engineer decides to configure a 5 Ghz frequency band SSID and train users to use that SSID for streaming media services. Why might this solution improve the wireless network performance for that type of service?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The 5 GHz band has more channels and is less crowded than the 2.4 GHz band, which makes it more suited to streaming multimedia."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "25. A network administrator is configuring a RADIUS server connection on a Cisco 3500 series WLC. The configuration requires a shared secret password. What is the purpose for the shared secret password?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is used to encrypt the messages between the WLC and the RADIUS server."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "26. Which three parameters would need to be changed if best practices are being implemented for a home wireless AP? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless network password"
      },
      {
        "answer": "AP password"
      },
      {
        "answer": "SSID"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "27. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol is based upon usernames and passwords?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "authentication"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "28. Which type of wireless network is based on the 802.11 standard and a 2.4-GHz or 5-GHz radio frequency?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless local-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "29. Which two Cisco solutions help prevent DHCP starvation attacks? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCP Snooping"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Port Security"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "30. What are three techniques for mitigating VLAN attacks? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Enable trunking manually."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Disable DTP."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Set the native VLAN to an unused VLAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "31. Refer to the exhibit. What can be determined about port security from the information that is shown?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The port violation mode is the default for any port that has port security enabled."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "32. A network administrator of a college is configuring the WLAN user authentication process. Wireless users are required to enter username and password credentials that will be verified by a server. Which server would provide such service?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "RADIUS"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "33. A technician is troubleshooting a slow WLAN that consists of 802.11b and 802.11g devices . A new 802.11n/ac dual-band router has been deployed on the network to replace the old 802.11g router. What can the technician do to address the slow wireless speed?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Split the wireless traffic between the 802.11n 2.4 GHz band and the 5 GHz band."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "34. The company handbook states that employees cannot have microwave ovens in their offices. Instead, all employees must use the microwave ovens located in the employee cafeteria. What wireless security risk is the company trying to avoid?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "accidental interference"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "35. What is the function provided by CAPWAP protocol in a corporate wireless network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "CAPWAP provides the encapsulation and forwarding of wireless user traffic between an access point and a wireless LAN controller."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which event will take place if there is a port security violation on switch S1 interface Fa0/1?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Packets with unknown source addresses will be dropped."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "38. What are two protocols that are used by AAA to authenticate users against a central database of usernames and password? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "TACACS+"
      },
      {
        "answer": "RADIUS"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "39. What is the result of a DHCP starvation attack?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Legitimate clients are unable to lease IP addresses."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "40. Which feature or configuration on a switch makes it vulnerable to VLAN double-tagging attacks?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the native VLAN of the trunking port being the same as a user VLAN"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "41. Which component of AAA allows an administrator to track individuals who access network resources and any changes that are made to those resources?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "accounting"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "42. Refer to the exhibit. PC1 and PC2 should be able to obtain IP address assignments from the DHCP server. How many ports among switches should be assigned as trusted ports as part of the DHCP snooping configuration?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "7"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "43. An IT security specialist enables port security on a switch port of a Cisco switch. What is the default violation mode in use until the switch port is configured to use a different violation mode?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "shutdown"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "44. A laptop cannot connect to a wireless access point. Which two troubleshooting steps should be taken first? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Ensure that the wireless NIC is enabled."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Ensure that the wireless SSID is chosen."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "45. What is an advantage of SSID cloaking?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Clients will have to manually identify the SSID to connect to the network.​"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "46. What is a wireless security mode that requires a RADIUS server to authenticate wireless users?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "enterprise"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "47. A company has recently implemented an 802.11n wireless network. Some users are complaining that the wireless network is too slow. Which solution is the best method to enhance the performance of the wireless network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Split the traffic between the 2.4 GHz and 5 GHz frequency bands."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "48. Which protocol can be used to monitor the network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SNMP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "49. A network administrator deploys a wireless router in a small law firm. Employee laptops join the WLAN and receive IP addresses in the 10.0.10.0/24 network. Which service is used on the wireless router to allow the employee laptops to access the internet?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "NAT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "50. Which service can be used on a wireless router to prioritize network traffic among different types of applications so that voice and video data are prioritized over email and web data?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "QoS"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "51. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol is based on device roles of supplicant, authenticator, and authentication server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "802.1X"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "52. Which type of wireless network is suitable for national and global communications?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless wide-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "53. Which feature on a switch makes it vulnerable to VLAN hopping attacks?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the automatic trunking port feature enabled for all ports by default"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "54. Which component of AAA is used to determine which resources a user can access and which operations the user is allowed to perform?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "authorization"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "55. Refer to the exhibit. The Fa0/2 interface on switch S1 has been configured with the switchport port-security mac-address 0023.189d.6456 command and a workstation has been connected. What could be the reason that the Fa0/2 interface is shutdown?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The MAC address of PC1 that connects to the Fa0/2 interface is not the configured MAC address."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the effect after these commands are entered?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "FastEthernet ports 5 through 10 can receive up to 6 DHCP discovery messages per second."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "57. A network administrator is configuring port security on a Cisco switch. The company security policy specifies that when a violation occurs, packets with unknown source addresses should be dropped and no notification should be sent. Which violation mode should be configured on the interfaces?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "protect"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "58. A network administrator is working to improve WLAN performance on a dual-band wireless router. What is a simple way to achieve a split-the-traffic result?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Make sure that different SSIDs are used for the 2.4 GHz and 5 GHz bands."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "59. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol controls what users can do on the network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "authorization"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "60. Which type of wireless network is suitable for providing wireless access to a city or district?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless metropolitan-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "61. On a Cisco 3504 WLC Summary page ( Advanced > Summary ), which tab allows a network administrator to access and configure a WLAN for a specific security option such as WPA2?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "WLANs"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "62. What type of wireless antenna is best suited for providing coverage in large open spaces, such as hallways or large conference rooms?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "omnidirectional"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "64. What security benefit is gained from enabling BPDU guard on PortFast enabled interfaces?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "preventing rogue switches from being added to the network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "65. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol logs EXEC and configuration commands configured by a user?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "accounting"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "66. Which type of wireless network uses transmitters to provide coverage over an extensive geographic area?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless wide-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "67. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol controls who is permitted to access a network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "authentication"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "68. What two IEEE 802.11 wireless standards operate only in the 5 GHz range? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "802.11ac"
      },
      {
        "answer": "802.11a"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "69. Which type of wireless network uses low powered transmitters for a short-range network, usually 20 to 30 ft. (6 to 9 meters)?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless personal-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "71. Which wireless network topology would be used by network engineers to provide a wireless network for an entire college building?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "infrastructure"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "72. Which type of wireless network uses transmitters to provide wireless service over a large urban region?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless metropolitan-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "73. Which type of wireless network is suitable for use in a home or office?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless local-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "74. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol indicates success or failure of a client-requested service with a PASS or FAIL message?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "authorization"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "75. Which type of wireless network often makes use of devices mounted on buildings?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless metropolitan-area network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "76. A network administrator is configuring DAI on a switch with the command ip arp inspection validate src-mac . What is the purpose of this configuration command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It checks the source MAC address in the Ethernet header against the sender MAC address in the ARP body."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "77. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol collects and reports usage data?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "accounting"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "78. Which type of wireless network uses transmitters to cover a medium-sized network, usually up to 300 feet (91.4 meters)?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Wireless LANs (WLAN)"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Accounting"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "82. A technician is troubleshooting a slow WLAN and decides to use the split-the-traffic approach. Which two parameters would have to be configured to do this? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure the 5 GHz band for streaming multimedia and time sensitive traffic."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Configure the 2.4 GHz band for basic internet traffic that is not time sensitive."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "83. Which access control component, implementation, or protocol restricts LAN access through publicly accessible switch ports?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "802.1X"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "84. A network administrator is required to upgrade wireless access to end users in a building. To provide data rates up to 1.3Gb/s and still be backward compatible with older devices, which wireless standard should be implemented?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "802.11a"
      },
      {
        "answer": "How to find:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "“Ctrl + F”"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Questions Bank"
      },
      {
        "answer": "NOTE: If you have the new question on this test, please comment Question and Multiple-Choice list in form below this article. We will update answers for you in the shortest time. Thank you! We truly value your contribution to the website."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "1. What additional information is contained in the 12-bit extended system ID of a BPDU?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "VLAN ID"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. During the implementation of Spanning Tree Protocol, all switches are rebooted by the network administrator. What is the first step of the spanning-tree election process?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "All the switches send out BPDUs advertising themselves as the root bridge."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Which STP port role is adopted by a switch port if there is no other port with a lower cost to the root bridge?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "root port"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Which two concepts relate to a switch port that is intended to have only end devices attached and intended never to be used to connect to another switch? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "edge port"
      },
      {
        "answer": "PortFast"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. Which three components are combined to form a bridge ID?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "extended system ID"
      },
      {
        "answer": "bridge priority"
      },
      {
        "answer": "MAC address"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. In which two port states does a switch learn MAC addresses and process BPDUs in a PVST network? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "forwarding"
      },
      {
        "answer": "learning"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. If no bridge priority is configured in PVST, which criteria is considered when electing the root bridge?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "lowest MAC address"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. When the show spanning-tree vlan 33 command is issued on a switch, three ports are shown in the forwarding state. In which two port roles could these interfaces function while in the forwarding state? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "designated"
      },
      {
        "answer": "root"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "11. What is the function of STP in a scalable network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It disables redundant paths to eliminate Layer 2 loops."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "12. What is a characteristic of spanning tree?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is enabled by default on Cisco switches."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "13. Which spanning tree standard supports only one root bridge so that traffic from all VLANs flows over the same path?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "802.1D"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "14. What is the purpose of the Spanning Tree Protocol (STP)?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "prevents Layer 2 loops"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "15. What is the value used to determine which port on a non-root bridge will become a root port in a STP network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the path cost"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "16. Refer to the exhibit. Which switch will be the root bridge after the election process is complete?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "S2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "17. What are two drawbacks to turning spanning tree off and having multiple paths through the Layer 2 switch network? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The MAC address table becomes unstable."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Broadcast frames are transmitted indefinitely."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "18. A small company network has six interconnected Layer 2 switches. Currently all switches are using the default bridge priority value. Which value can be used to configure the bridge priority of one of the switches to ensure that it becomes the root bridge in this design?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "28672"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "19. Refer to the exhibit. The administrator tried to create an EtherChannel between S1 and the other two switches via the commands that are shown, but was unsuccessful. What is the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Traffic cannot be sent to two different switches through the same EtherChannel link."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "20. Which statement is true regarding the use of PAgP to create EtherChannels?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is Cisco proprietary."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "21. What are two requirements to be able to configure an EtherChannel between two switches? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "All the interfaces need to work at the same speed."
      },
      {
        "answer": "All the interfaces need to be working in the same duplex mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. On the basis of the output that is shown, what can be determined about the EtherChannel bundle?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A Cisco proprietary protocol was used to negotiate the EtherChannel link."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "23. Which two parameters must match on the ports of two switches to create a PAgP EtherChannel between the switches? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "speed"
      },
      {
        "answer": "VLAN information"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "24. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring an EtherChannel link between two switches, SW1 and SW2. Which statement describes the effect after the commands are issued on SW1 and SW2?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The EtherChannel fails to establish."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "25. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring an EtherChannel link between two switches, SW1 and SW2. However, the EtherChannel link fails to establish. What change in configuration would correct the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure SW2 EtherChannel mode to desirable."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "26. A network administrator configured an EtherChannel link with three interfaces between two switches. What is the result if one of the three interfaces is down?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The remaining two interfaces continue to load balance traffic."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "27. A network administrator is configuring an EtherChannel link between switches SW1 and SW2 by using the command SW1(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode auto . Which command must be used on SW2 to enable this EtherChannel?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SW2(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode desirable"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "28. Which technology is an open protocol standard that allows switches to automatically bundle physical ports into a single logical link?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "LACP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "29. What is a requirement to configure a trunking EtherChannel between two switches?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The allowed range of VLANs must be the same on both switches."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "30. What are two advantages of using LACP? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It allows directly connected switches to negotiate an EtherChannel link."
      },
      {
        "answer": "It allows the use of multivendor devices."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "31. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes a non-root port that is permitted to forward traffic on the network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "designated port"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "32. What are two advantages of EtherChannel? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Spanning Tree Protocol views the physical links in an EtherChannel as one logical connection."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Configuring the EtherChannel interface provides consistency in the configuration of the physical links."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "33. Refer to the exhibit. What are the possible port roles for ports A, B, C, and D in this RSTP-enabled network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "alternate, designated, root, root"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "34. Refer to the exhibit. Which switching technology would allow each access layer switch link to be aggregated to provide more bandwidth between each Layer 2 switch and the Layer 3 switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "EtherChannel"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "35. Refer to the exhibit. An administrator wants to form an EtherChannel between the two switches by using the Port Aggregation Protocol. If switch S1 is configured to be in auto mode, which mode should be configured on S2 to form the EtherChannel?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "desirable"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which set of configuration commands issued on SW1 will successfully complete the EtherChannel link between SW1 and SW2?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "interface GigabitEthernet0/1"
      },
      {
        "answer": "channel-group 1 mode desirable"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "37. A set of switches is being connected in a LAN topology. Which STP bridge priority value will make it least likely for the switch to be selected as the root?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "61440"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "38. In which two PVST+ port states are MAC addresses learned? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "learning"
      },
      {
        "answer": "forwarding"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "39. Which port role is assigned to the switch port that has the lowest cost to reach the root bridge?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "root port"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "40. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes the switch port closest, in terms of overall cost, to the root bridge?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "root port"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "42. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes a field used to specify a VLAN ID?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "extended system ID"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "43. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes the reference point for all path calculations?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "root bridge"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "44. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes a field that has a default value of 32,768 and is the initial deciding factor when electing a root bridge?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "bridge priority"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "45. Which statement describes an EtherChannel implementation?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A trunked port can be part of an EtherChannel bundle."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "46. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator issued the show etherchannel summary command on the switch S1. What conclusion can be drawn?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The EtherChannel is not functional."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "47. Which statement describes a characteristic of EtherChannel?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is made by combining multiple physical links that are seen as one link between two switches."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "48. Which two channel group modes would place an interface in a negotiating state using PAgP? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "desirable"
      },
      {
        "answer": "auto"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "49. Which mode configuration setting would allow formation of an EtherChannel link between switches SW1 and SW2 without sending negotiation traffic?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SW1: on\nSW2: on"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "50. Refer to the exhibit. An EtherChannel was configured between switches S1 and S2, but the interfaces do not form an EtherChannel. What is the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The EtherChannel was not configured with the same allowed range of VLANs on each interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "51. When EtherChannel is configured, which mode will force an interface into a port channel without exchanging aggregation protocol packets?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "on"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "52. What are two load-balancing methods in the EtherChannel technology? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "source IP to destination IP"
      },
      {
        "answer": "source MAC to destination MAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "53. Which protocol provides up to 16 instances of RSTP, combines many VLANs with the same physical and logical topology into a common RSTP instance, and provides support for PortFast, BPDU guard, BPDU filter, root guard, and loop guard?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "MST"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "54. What is the outcome of a Layer 2 broadcast storm?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "New traffic is discarded by the switch because it is unable to be processed."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "55. Which two network design features require Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) to ensure correct network operation? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "redundant links between Layer 2 switches"
      },
      {
        "answer": "removing single points of failure with multiple Layer 2 switches"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "56. A network administrator has configured an EtherChannel between two switches that are connected via four trunk links. If the physical interface for one of the trunk links changes to a down state, what happens to the EtherChannel?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The EtherChannel will remain functional."
      },
      {
        "answer": "How to find:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "“Ctrl + F”"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Questions Bank"
      },
      {
        "answer": "NOTE: If you have the new question on this test, please comment Question and Multiple-Choice list in form below this article. We will update answers for you in the shortest time. Thank you! We truly value your contribution to the website."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "1. Which feature on a Cisco router permits the forwarding of traffic for which there is no specific route?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "gateway of last resort"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. Which three advantages are provided by static routing? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Static routing does not advertise over the network, thus providing better security."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Static routing typically uses less network bandwidth and fewer CPU operations than dynamic routing does."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The path a static route uses to send data is known."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. What are two functions of dynamic routing protocols? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to maintain routing tables"
      },
      {
        "answer": "to discover the network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. What is an advantage of using dynamic routing protocols instead of static routing?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ability to actively search for new routes if the current path becomes unavailable​"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What happens to a static route entry in a routing table when the outgoing interface associated with that route goes into the down state?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The static route is removed from the routing table."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What is a characteristic of a static route that matches all packets?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It identifies the gateway IP address to which the router sends all IP packets for which it does not have a learned or static route."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. When would it be more beneficial to use a dynamic routing protocol instead of static routing?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "on a network where there is a lot of topology changes"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. Which route would be used to forward a packet with a source IP address of 192.168.10.1 and a destination IP address of 10.1.1.1?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "O 10.1.1.0/24 [110/65] via 192.168.200.2, 00:01:20, Serial0/1/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Refer to the exhibit. What is the administrative distance value of the route for router R1 to reach the destination IPv6 address of 2001:DB8:CAFE:4::A?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "120"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. Which value in a routing table represents trustworthiness and is used by the router to determine which route to install into the routing table when there are multiple routes toward the same destination?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "administrative distance"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "12. Refer to the graphic. Which command would be used on router A to configure a static route to direct traffic from LAN A that is destined for LAN C?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A(config)# ip route 192.168.4.0 255.255.255.0 192.168.3.2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "13. On which two routers would a default static route be configured? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "stub router connection to the rest of the corporate or campus network"
      },
      {
        "answer": "edge router connection to the ISP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "14. Refer to the exhibit. This network has two connections to the ISP, one via router C and one via router B. The serial link between router A and router C supports EIGRP and is the primary link to the Internet. If the primary link fails, the administrator needs a floating static route that avoids recursive route lookups and any potential next-hop issues caused by the multiaccess nature of the Ethernet segment with router B. What should the administrator configure?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Create a fully specified static route pointing to Fa0/0 with an AD of 95."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "15. What is a characteristic of a floating static route?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is configured with a higher administrative distance than the original dynamic routing protocol has."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "16. What network prefix and prefix-length combination is used to create a default static route that will match any IPv6 destination?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "::/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the 5 at the end of the command signify?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "administrative distance"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What will router R2 do with a packet destined for 192.168.10.129?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "send the packet out interface Serial0/0/1"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "19. An administrator issues the ipv6 route 2001:db8:acad:1::/32 gigabitethernet0/0 2001:db8:acad:6::1 100 command on a router. What administrative distance is assigned to this route?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "100"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "20. Refer to the exhibit. Which default static route command would allow R1 to potentially reach all unknown networks on the Internet?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "R1(config)# ipv6 route ::/0 G0/1 fe80::2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "21. Refer to the exhibit. The network engineer for the company that is shown wants to use the primary ISP connection for all external connectivity. The backup ISP connection is used only if the primary ISP connection fails. Which set of commands would accomplish this goal?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 s0/0/0"
      },
      {
        "answer": "ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 s0/1/0 10"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. Which set of commands will configure static routes that will allow the Park and the Alta routers to a) forward packets to each LAN and b) direct all other traffic to the Internet?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Park(config)# ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 192.168.14.1"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Alta(config)# ip route 10.0.234.0 255.255.255.0 192.168.14.2"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Alta(config)# ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 s0/0/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "23. Refer to the exhibit. The small company shown uses static routing. Users on the R2 LAN have reported a problem with connectivity. What is the issue?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "R1 needs a static route to the R2 LAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "24. Refer to the exhibit. An administrator is attempting to install an IPv6 static route on router R1 to reach the network attached to router R2. After the static route command is entered, connectivity to the network is still failing. What error has been made in the static route configuration?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The interface is incorrect."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "25. Refer to the exhibit. How was the host route 2001:DB8:CAFE:4::1/128 installed in the routing table?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The route was manually entered by an administrator."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "26. Refer to the exhibit. HostA is attempting to contact ServerB. Which two statements correctly describe the addressing that HostA will generate in the process? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A packet with the destination IP address of ServerB."
      },
      {
        "answer": "A frame with the destination MAC address of RouterA."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "27. Refer to the exhibit. A ping from R1 to 10.1.1.2 is successful, but a ping from R1 to any address in the 192.168.2.0 network fails. What is the cause of this problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The static route for 192.168.2.0 is incorrectly configured."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "28. Refer to the exhibit. An administrator is attempting to install a default static route on router R1 to reach the Site B network on router R2. After entering the static route command, the route is still not showing up in the routing table of router R1. What is preventing the route from installing in the routing table?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The next hop address is incorrect."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "29. Refer to the exhibit. The Branch Router has an OSPF neighbor relationship with the HQ router over the 198.51.0.4/30 network. The 198.51.0.8/30 network link should serve as a backup when the OSPF link goes down. The floating static route command ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 S0/1/1 100 was issued on Branch and now traffic is using the backup link even when the OSPF link is up and functioning. Which change should be made to the static route command so that traffic will only use the OSPF link when it is up?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Change the administrative distance to 120."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "30. What characteristic completes the following statement?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "When an IPv6 static route is configured, the next-hop address can be ……"
      },
      {
        "answer": "an IPv6 link-local address on the adjacent router."
      },
      {
        "answer": "31. Gateway of last resort is not set."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the exhibit. Which interface will be the exit interface to forward a data packet that has the destination IP address 172.19.115.206?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "GigabitEthernet0/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "32. Refer to the exhibit. What routing solution will allow both PC A and PC B to access the Internet with the minimum amount of router CPU and network bandwidth utilization?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure a static default route from R1 to Edge, a default route from Edge to the Internet, and a static route from Edge to R1."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "33. Refer to the exhibit. What would happen after the IT administrator enters the new static route?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The 172.16.1.0 route learned from RIP would be replaced with the 172.16.1.0 static route."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "34. What two pieces of information are needed in a fully specified static route to eliminate recursive lookups? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the interface ID exit interface"
      },
      {
        "answer": "the IP address of the next-hop neighbor"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "35. Refer to the exhibit. Which command will properly configure an IPv6 static route on R2 that will allow traffic from PC2 to reach PC1 without any recursive lookups by router R2?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "R2(config)# ipv6 route 2001:db8:10:12::/64 S0/0/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "36. Refer to the exhibit. Which static route would an IT technician enter to create a backup route to the 172.16.1.0 network that is only used if the primary RIP learned route fails?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip route 172.16.1.0 255.255.255.0 s0/0/0 121"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the cause of the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Routing between HQ and Branch is configured incorrectly."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "39. Refer to the exhibit. PC A sends a request to Server B. What IPv4 address is used in the destination field in the packet as the packet leaves PC A?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "192.168.12.16"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "40. What does R1 use as the MAC address of the destination when constructing the frame that will go from R1 to Server B?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "If the destination MAC address that corresponds to the IPv4 address is not in the ARP cache, R1 sends an ARP request."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "41. What route would have the lowest administrative distance?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "a directly connected network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "42. What characteristic completes the following statement?\nWhen an IPv6 static route is configured, as a backup route to a static route in the routing table, the “distance” command is used with ……",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "an administrative distance of 2."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "43. A router has used the OSPF protocol to learn a route to the 172.16.32.0/19 network. Which command will implement a backup floating static route to this network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip route 172.16.32.0 255.255.224.0 S0/0/0 200"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How would an administrator test this configuration?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Manually shut down the router interface used as a primary route."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "45. Refer to the exhibit. Which type of IPv6 static route is configured in the exhibit?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "recursive static route"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "46. What characteristic completes the following statement?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "When an IPv6 static route is configured, it is first necessary to configure ……"
      },
      {
        "answer": "the “ipv6 unicast-routing” command."
      },
      {
        "answer": "47. Gateway of last resort is not set."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the exhibit. Which interface will be the exit interface to forward a data packet that has the destination IP address 172.18.109.152?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Serial0/0/0"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Send the packet out the Serial0/0/0 interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "50. What are two advantages of static routing over dynamic routing? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Static routing is more secure because it does not advertise over the network."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Static routing uses fewer router resources than dynamic routing."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "51. What characteristic completes the following statement?\nWhen an IPv6 static route is configured, it is possible that the same IPv6 link-local address is used for …",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the next-hop address of two different adjacent routers."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "52. A network administrator configures the interface fa0/0 on the router R1 with the command ip address 172.16.1.254 255.255.255.0. However, when the administrator issues the command show ip route, the routing table does not show the directly connected network. What is the possible cause of the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The interface fa0/0 has not been activated."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "53. Refer to the exhibit. What command would be used to configure a static route on R1 so that traffic from both LANs can reach the 2001:db8:1:4::/64 remote network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 route 2001:db8:1:4::/64 2001:db8:1:3::2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "54. Refer to the exhibit. What two commands will change the next-hop address for the 10.0.0.0/8 network from 172.16.40.2 to 192.168.1.2? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "A(config)# ip route 10.0.0.0 255.0.0.0 192.168.1.2"
      },
      {
        "answer": "A(config)# no ip route 10.0.0.0 255.0.0.0 172.16.40.2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "55. Refer to the exhibit. Which interface will be the exit interface to forward a data packet that has the destination IP address 192.168.139.244?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "GigabitEthernet0/1"
      },
      {
        "answer": "a directly connected multiaccess network."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Serial0/0/0"
      },
      {
        "answer": "the “show ipv6 route static” command."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Serial0/0/1"
      },
      {
        "answer": "The interface fa0/0 has not been activated."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "61. Refer to the exhibit. Which interface will be the exit interface to forward a data packet that has the destination IP address 10.3.86.2?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Serial0/0/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "1. Refer to the exhibit. What will router R1 do with a packet that has a destination IPv6 address of 2001:db8:cafe:5::1?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "forward the packet out Serial0/0/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. Refer to the exhibit. Currently router R1 uses an EIGRP route learned from Branch2 to reach the 10.10.0.0/16 network. Which floating static route would create a backup route to the 10.10.0.0/16 network in the event that the link between R1 and Branch2 goes down?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip route 10.10.0.0 255.255.0.0 209.165.200.225 100"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Refer to the exhibit. R1 was configured with the static route command ip route 209.165.200.224 255.255.255.224 S0/0/0 and consequently users on network 172.16.0.0/16 are unable to reach resources on the Internet. How should this static route be changed to allow user traffic from the LAN to reach the Internet?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Change the destination network and mask to 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Which option shows a correctly configured IPv4 default static route?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 S0/0/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. Refer to the exhibit. Which static route command can be entered on R1 to forward traffic to the LAN connected to R2?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 route 2001:db8:12:10::/64 S0/0/1 fe80::2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What is a method to launch a VLAN hopping attack?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "introducing a rogue switch and enabling trunking"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. A cybersecurity analyst is using the macof tool to evaluate configurations of switches deployed in the backbone network of an organization. Which type of LAN attack is the analyst targeting during this evaluation?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "MAC address table overflow"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring a router as a DHCPv6 server. The administrator issues a show ipv6 dhcp pool command to verify the configuration. Which statement explains the reason that the number of active clients is 0?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The state is not maintained by the DHCPv6 server under stateless DHCPv6 operation."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator configured routers R1 and R2 as part of HSRP group 1. After the routers have been reloaded, a user on Host1 complained of lack of connectivity to the Internet The network administrator issued the show standby brief command on both routers to verify the HSRP operations. In addition, the administrator observed the ARP table on Host1. Which entry should be seen in the ARP table on Host1 in order to gain connectivity to the Internet?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the virtual IP address and the virtual MAC address for the HSRP group 1"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "11. Which statement is correct about how a Layer 2 switch determines how to forward frames?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Frame forwarding decisions are based on MAC address and port mappings in the CAM table."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "12. Which statement describes a result after multiple Cisco LAN switches are interconnected?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The broadcast domain expands to all switches."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "14.Refer to the exhibit. How is a frame sent from PCA forwarded to PCC if the MAC address table on switch SW1 is empty?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SW1 floods the frame on all ports on SW1, excluding the port through which the frame entered the switch."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "15. An administrator is trying to remove configurations from a switch. After using the command erase startup-config and reloading the switch, the administrator finds that VLANs 10 and 100 still exist on the switch. Why were these VLANs not removed?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Because these VLANs are stored in a file that is called vlan.dat that is located in flash memory, this file must be manually deleted."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "17. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator has connected two switches together using EtherChannel technology. If STP is running, what will be the end result?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "STP will block one of the redundant links."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "18. What is a secure configuration option for remote access to a network device?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure SSH."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "19. Which wireless encryption method is the most secure?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "WPA2 with AES"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "20. After attaching four PCs to the switch ports, configuring the SSID and setting authentication properties for a small office network, a technician successfully tests the connectivity of all PCs that are connected to the switch and WLAN. A firewall is then configured on the device prior to connecting it to the Internet. What type of network device includes all of the described features?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "wireless router"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "21. Refer to the exhibit. Host A has sent a packet to host B. What will be the source MAC and IP addresses on the packet when it arrives at host B?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Source MAC: 00E0.FE91.7799"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Source IP: 10.1.1.10"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of this command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Packets with a destination network that is not 10.10.0.0/16 or is not 10.20.0.0/16 or is not a directly connected network will be forwarded to the Internet."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "24. What protocol or technology disables redundant paths to eliminate Layer 2 loops?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "STP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "25. Refer to the exhibit. Based on the exhibited configuration and output, why is VLAN 99 missing?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "because VLAN 99 has not yet been created"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "26. Which two VTP modes allow for the creation, modification, and deletion of VLANs on the local switch? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "server"
      },
      {
        "answer": "transparent"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "27. Which three steps should be taken before moving a Cisco switch to a new VTP management domain? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure the switch with the name of the new management domain."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Select the correct VTP mode and version."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Reboot the switch."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "28. A network administrator is preparing the implementation of Rapid PVST+ on a production network. How are the Rapid PVST+ link types determined on the switch interfaces?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Link types are determined automatically."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "29. Refer to the exhibit. All the displayed switches are Cisco 2960 switches with the same default priority and operating at the same bandwidth. Which three ports will be STP designated ports? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "fa0/13"
      },
      {
        "answer": "fa0/10"
      },
      {
        "answer": "fa0/21"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "30. How will a router handle static routing differently if Cisco Express Forwarding is disabled?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Ethernet multiaccess interfaces will require fully specified static routes to avoid routing inconsistencies."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "31. Compared with dynamic routes, what are two advantages of using static routes on a router? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "They improve netw​ork security."
      },
      {
        "answer": "They use fewer router resources."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "32. Refer to the exhibit. Which route was configured as a static route to a specific network using the next-hop address?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "S 10.17.2.0/24 [1/0] via 10.16.2.2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "33. What is the effect of entering the spanning-tree portfast configuration command on a switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It enables portfast on a specific switch interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "34. What is the IPv6 prefix that is used for link-local addresses?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "FE80::/10"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "35. Which two statements are characteristics of routed ports on a multilayer switch? (Choose two.)​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "In a switched network, they are mostly configured between switches at the core and distribution layers."
      },
      {
        "answer": "They are not associated with a particular VLAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "36. Successful inter-VLAN routing has been operating on a network with multiple VLANs across multiple switches for some time. When an inter-switch trunk link fails and Spanning Tree Protocol brings up a backup trunk link, it is reported that hosts on two VLANs can access some, but not all the network resources that could be accessed previously. Hosts on all other VLANS do not have this problem. What is the most likely cause of this problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The protected edge port function on the backup trunk interfaces has been disabled."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "37. Which command will start the process to bundle two physical interfaces to create an EtherChannel group via LACP?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "interface range GigabitEthernet 0/4 – 5"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "38. What action takes place when a frame entering a switch has a multicast destination MAC address?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The switch will forward the frame out all ports except the incoming port."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "39. A junior technician was adding a route to a LAN router. A traceroute to a device on the new network revealed a wrong path and unreachable status. What should be done or checked?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Check the configuration of the exit interface on the new static route."
      },
      {
        "answer": "40. Select the three PAgP channel establishment modes. (Choose three.)"
      },
      {
        "answer": "auto"
      },
      {
        "answer": "desirable"
      },
      {
        "answer": "on"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "41. A static route has been configured on a router. However, the destination network no longer exists. What should an administrator do to remove the static route from the routing table?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Remove the route using the no ip route command."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "42. Refer to the exhibit. What can be concluded about the configuration shown on R1?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "R1 is configured as a DHCPv4 relay agent."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "44. Refer to the exhibit. R1 has been configured as shown. However, PC1 is not able to receive an IPv4 address. What is the problem?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The ip helper-address command was applied on the wrong interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "45. What two default wireless router settings can affect network security? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The SSID is broadcast."
      },
      {
        "answer": "A well-known administrator password is set."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "46. What is the common term given to SNMP log messages that are generated by network devices and sent to the SNMP server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "traps"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "47. A network administrator is adding a new WLAN on a Cisco 3500 series WLC. Which tab should the administrator use to create a new VLAN interface to be used for the new WLAN?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "CONTROLLER"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "48. A network administrator is configuring a WLAN. Why would the administrator change the default DHCP IPv4 addresses on an AP?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to reduce outsiders intercepting data or accessing the wireless network by using a well-known address range"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "49. Which two functions are performed by a WLC when using split media access control (MAC)? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "frame translation to other protocols"
      },
      {
        "answer": "association and re-association of roaming clients"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "50. On what switch ports should BPDU guard be enabled to enhance STP stability?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "all PortFast-enabled ports"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "51. Which network attack is mitigated by enabling BPDU guard?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "rogue switches on a network"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "52. Why is DHCP snooping required when using the Dynamic ARP Inspection feature?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It uses the MAC-address-to-IP-address binding database to validate an ARP packet."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "53. Refer to the exhibit. Router R1 has an OSPF neighbor relationship with the ISP router over the 192.168.0.32 network. The 192.168.0.36 network link should serve as a backup when the OSPF link goes down. The floating static route command ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 S0/0/1 100 was issued on R1 and now traffic is using the backup link even when the OSPF link is up and functioning. Which change should be made to the static route command so that traffic will only use the OSPF link when it is up?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Change the administrative distance to 120."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "54. Refer to the exhibit. What is the metric to forward a data packet with the IPv6 destination address 2001:DB8:ACAD:E:240:BFF:FED4:9DD2?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "2682112"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "55. A network administrator is configuring a new Cisco switch for remote management access. Which three items must be configured on the switch for the task? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "IP address"
      },
      {
        "answer": "vty lines"
      },
      {
        "answer": "default gateway"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "56. Refer to the exhibit. Which statement shown in the output allows router R1 to respond to stateless DHCPv6 requests?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 nd other-config-flag​"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "57. Refer to the exhibit. A Layer 3 switch routes for three VLANs and connects to a router for Internet connectivity. Which two configurations would be applied to the switch? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "(config)# interface gigabitethernet 1/1\n(config-if)# no switchport\n(config-if)# ip address 192.168.1.2 255.255.255.252"
      },
      {
        "answer": "(config)# ip routing"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "58. A technician is troubleshooting a slow WLAN and decides to use the split-the-traffic approach. Which two parameters would have to be configured to do this? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure the 5 GHz band for streaming multimedia and time sensitive traffic."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Configure the 2.4 GHz band for basic internet traffic that is not time sensitive."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "59. A company has just switched to a new ISP. The ISP has completed and checked the connection from its site to the company. However, employees at the company are not able to access the internet. What should be done or checked?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Ensure that the old default route has been removed from the company edge routers."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "60. Which information does a switch use to populate the MAC address table?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the source MAC address and the incoming port"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "61. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is reviewing the configuration of switch S1. Which protocol has been implemented to group multiple physical ports into one logical link?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "PAgP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "62. Which type of static route is configured with a greater administrative distance to provide a backup route to a route learned from a dynamic routing protocol?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "floating static route"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "63. What action takes place when a frame entering a switch has a unicast destination MAC address appearing in the MAC address table?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The switch forwards the frame out of the specified port."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "64. The exhibit shows two PCs called PC A and PC B, two routes called R1 and R2, and two switches. PC A has the address 172.16.1.1/24 and is connected to a switch and into an interface on R1 that has the IP address 172.16.1.254. PC B has the address 172.16.2.1/24 and is connected to a switch that is connected to another interface on R1 with the IP address 172.16.2.254. The serial interface on R1 has the address 172.16.3.1 and is connected to the serial interface on R2 that has the address 172.16.3.2/24. R2 is connected to the internet cloud. Which command will create a static route on R2 in order to reach PC B?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "R2(config)# ip route 172.16.2.0 255.255.255.0 172.16.3.1"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "65. What protocol or technology allows data to transmit over redundant switch links?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "STP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "66. Refer to the exhibit. Which three hosts will receive ARP requests from host A, assuming that port Fa0/4 on both switches is configured to carry traffic for multiple VLANs? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "host C"
      },
      {
        "answer": "host D"
      },
      {
        "answer": "host F"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "67. Refer to the exhibit. The network administrator configures both switches as displayed. However, host C is unable to ping host D and host E is unable to ping host F. What action should the administrator take to enable this communication?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure either trunk port in the dynamic desirable mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "68. What is the effect of entering the shutdown configuration command on a switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It disables an unused port."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "69. What would be the primary reason an attacker would launch a MAC address overflow attack?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "so that the attacker can see frames that are destined for other hosts"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "70. During the AAA process, when will authorization be implemented?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Immediately after successful authentication against an AAA data source"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "71. A company security policy requires that all MAC addressing be dynamically learned and added to both the MAC address table and the running configuration on each switch. Which port security configuration will accomplish this?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "sticky secure MAC addresses"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "72. Which three Wi-Fi standards operate in the 2.4GHz range of frequencies? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "802.11b"
      },
      {
        "answer": "802.11g"
      },
      {
        "answer": "802.11n"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "73. To obtain an overview of the spanning tree status of a switched network, a network engineer issues the show spanning-tree command on a switch. Which two items of information will this command display? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The root bridge BID."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The role of the ports in all VLANs."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "74. Refer to the exhibit. Which trunk link will not forward any traffic after the root bridge election process is complete?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Trunk2"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "75. Which method of IPv6 prefix assignment relies on the prefix contained in RA messages?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SLAAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "76. Which two protocols are used to provide server-based AAA authentication? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "TACACS+"
      },
      {
        "answer": "RADIUS"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "77. A network administrator is configuring a WLAN. Why would the administrator disable the broadcast feature for the SSID?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to eliminate outsiders scanning for available SSIDs in the area"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "78. Which mitigation technique would prevent rogue servers from providing false IP configuration parameters to clients?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "turning on DHCP snooping"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "79. A network administrator configures the port security feature on a switch. The security policy specifies that each access port should allow up to two MAC addresses. When the maximum number of MAC addresses is reached, a frame with the unknown source MAC address is dropped and a notification is sent to the syslog server. Which security violation mode should be configured for each access port?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "restrict"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "80. What protocol or technology defines a group of routers, one of them defined as active and another one as standby?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "HSRP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "81. Refer to the exhibit. After attempting to enter the configuration that is shown in router RTA, an administrator receives an error and users on VLAN 20 report that they are unable to reach users on VLAN 30. What is causing the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "RTA is using the same subnet for VLAN 20 and VLAN 30."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "82. Which three pairs of trunking modes will establish a functional trunk link between two Cisco switches? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": []
  },
  {
    "question": "83. A technician is configuring a router for a small company with multiple WLANs and doesn’t need the complexity of a dynamic routing protocol. What should be done or checked?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Create static routes to all internal networks and a default route to the internet."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "84. A company is deploying a wireless network in the distribution facility in a Boston suburb. The warehouse is quite large and it requires multiple access points to be used. Because some of the company devices still operate at 2.4GHz, the network administrator decides to deploy the 802.11g standard. Which channel assignments on the multiple access points will make sure that the wireless channels are not overlapping?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "channels 1, 6, and 11"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "85. A network administrator of a small advertising company is configuring WLAN security by using the WPA2 PSK method. Which credential do office users need in order to connect their laptops to the WLAN?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "a user passphrase"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "86. Refer to the exhibit. What are the possible port roles for ports A, B, C, and D in this RSTP-enabled network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "alternate, designated, root, root"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "87. Refer to the exhibit. Which static route would an IT technician enter to create a backup route to the 172.16.1.0 network that is only used if the primary RIP learned route fails?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "ip route 172.16.1.0 255.255.255.0 s0/0/0 121"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "88. What mitigation plan is best for thwarting a DoS attack that is creating a MAC address table overflow?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Enable port security."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "89. A network engineer is troubleshooting a newly deployed wireless network that is using the latest 802.11 standards. When users access high bandwidth services such as streaming video, the wireless network performance is poor. To improve performance the network engineer decides to configure a 5 Ghz frequency band SSID and train users to use that SSID for streaming media services. Why might this solution improve the wireless network performance for that type of service?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The 5 GHz band has more channels and is less crowded than the 2.4 GHz band, which makes it more suited to streaming multimedia."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "90. Which DHCPv4 message will a client send to accept an IPv4 address that is offered by a DHCP server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "broadcast DHCPREQUEST"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "91. Refer to the exhibit. Which destination MAC address is used when frames are sent from the workstation to the default gateway?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "MAC address of the virtual router"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "92. After a host has generated an IPv6 address by using the DHCPv6 or SLAAC process, how does the host verify that the address is unique and therefore usable?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The host sends an ICMPv6 neighbor solicitation message to the DHCP or SLAAC-learned address and if no neighbor advertisement is returned, the address is considered unique."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "94. Which protocol adds security to remote connections?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "SSH"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "95. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is verifying the configuration of inter-VLAN routing. Users complain that PC2 cannot communicate with PC1. Based on the output, what is the possible cause of the problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The encapsulation dot1Q 5 command contains the wrong VLAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "96. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring inter-VLAN routing on a network. For now, only one VLAN is being used, but more will be added soon. What is the missing parameter that is shown as the highlighted question mark in the graphic?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It identifies the VLAN number."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "98. What network attack seeks to create a DoS for clients by preventing them from being able to obtain a DHCP lease?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DHCP starvation"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "99. Refer to the exhibit. If the IP addresses of the default gateway router and the DNS server are correct, what is the configuration problem?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The IP address of the default gateway router is not contained in the excluded address list."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "100. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator has added a new subnet to the network and needs hosts on that subnet to receive IPv4 addresses from the DHCPv4 server.\nWhat two commands will allow hosts on the new subnet to receive addresses from the DHCP4 server? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "R1(config-if)# ip helper-address 10.2.0.250"
      },
      {
        "answer": "R1(config)# interface G0/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "101. What protocol or technology uses source IP to destination IP as a load-balancing mechanism?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "EtherChannel"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "102. What protocol should be disabled to help mitigate VLAN attacks?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DTP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "103. What protocol or technology requires switches to be in server mode or client mode?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "VTP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "104. What are two reasons a network administrator would segment a network with a Layer 2 switch? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to enhance user bandwidth"
      },
      {
        "answer": "to isolate traffic between segments"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "105. What command will enable a router to begin sending messages that allow it to configure a link-local address without using an IPv6 DHCP server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "the ipv6 unicast-routing command"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "106. A network administrator is using the router-on-a-stick model to configure a switch and a router for inter-VLAN routing. What configuration should be made on the switch port that connects to the router?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure the port as an 802.1q trunk port."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "107. What are three techniques for mitigating VLAN attacks? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Enable trunking manually"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Disable DTP."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Set the native VLAN to an unused VLAN."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "109. In which situation would a technician use the show interfaces switch command?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "when packets are being dropped from a particular directly attached host"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "110. What is a drawback of the local database method of securing device access that can be solved by using AAA with centralized servers?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "User accounts must be configured locally on each device, which is an unscalable authentication solution."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "111. What action does a DHCPv4 client take if it receives more than one DHCPOFFER from multiple DHCP servers?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It sends a DHCPREQUEST that identifies which lease offer the client is accepting."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "112. Refer to the exhibit. The network administrator is configuring the port security feature on switch SWC. The administrator issued the command show port-security interface fa 0/2 to verify the configuration. What can be concluded from the output that is shown? (Choose three.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "This port is currently up."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Security violations will cause this port to shut down immediately."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The switch port mode for this interface is access mode."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "113. What method of wireless authentication is dependent on a RADIUS authentication server?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "WPA2 Enterprise"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "114. A network administrator has found a user sending a double-tagged 802.1Q frame to a switch. What is the best solution to prevent this type of attack?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The VLANs for user access ports should be different VLANs than any native VLANs used on trunk ports."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "115. Refer to the exhibit. Which two conclusions can be drawn from the output? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The EtherChannel is down."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The port channel ID is 2."
      },
      {
        "answer": "WLANs"
      },
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 route ::/0 serial 0/1/1"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Check the statistics on the default route for oversaturation."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The switch replaces the old entry and uses the more current port."
      },
      {
        "answer": "to facilitate group configuration and management of multiple WLANs through a WLC"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Case 2:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Case 3:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Case 4:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Case 5:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Case 6:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "Reference:"
      },
      {
        "answer": "An autonegotiation failure can result in connectivity issues."
      },
      {
        "answer": "When the speed is set to 1000 Mb/s, the switch ports will operate in full-duplex mode."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The duplex and speed settings of each switch port can be manually configured."
      },
      {
        "answer": "B. The encapsulation is misconfigured on a subinterface."
      },
      {
        "answer": "PortFast is not configured on all access ports."
      },
      {
        "answer": "RSTP"
      },
      {
        "answer": "STP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "127. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring the router R1 for IPv6 address assignment. Based on the partial configuration, which IPv6 global unicast address assignment scheme does the administrator intend to implement?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "stateful"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "128. A WLAN engineer deploys a WLC and five wireless APs using the CAPWAP protocol with the DTLS feature to secure the control plane of the network devices. While testing the wireless network, the WLAN engineer notices that data traffic is being exchanged between the WLC and the APs in plain-text and is not being encrypted. What is the most likely reason for this?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Although DTLS is enabled by default to secure the CAPWAP control channel, it is disabled by default for the data channel."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "129. A new switch is to be added to an existing network in a remote office. The network administrator does not want the technicians in the remote office to be able to add new VLANs to the switch, but the switch should receive VLAN updates from the VTP domain. Which two steps must be performed to configure VTP on the new switch to meet these conditions? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Configure the new switch as a VTP client."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Configure the existing VTP domain name on the new switch."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "130. Refer to the exhibit. Consider that the main power has just been restored. PC3 issues a broadcast IPv4 DHCP request. To which port will SW1 forward this request?​",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to Fa0/1, Fa0/2, and Fa0/3 only"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "131. What action takes place when the source MAC address of a frame entering a switch is not in the MAC address table?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The switch adds the MAC address and incoming port number to the table."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Use the “show ip interface brief” command to see if an interface is down."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "133. What is the effect of entering the ip dhcp snooping configuration command on a switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It enables DHCP snooping globally on a switch."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Check the routing table for a missing static route."
      },
      {
        "answer": "fast internal switching"
      },
      {
        "answer": "large frame buffers"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "136. What is a result of connecting two or more switches together?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The size of the broadcast domain is increased."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "138. Branch users were able to access a site in the morning but have had no connectivity with the site since lunch time. What should be done or checked?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Use the “show ip interface brief” command to see if an interface is down."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "139. What is the effect of entering the switchport port-security configuration command on a switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It enables port security on an interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "140. A network administrator is configuring a WLAN. Why would the administrator use multiple lightweight APs?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to facilitate group configuration and management of multiple WLANs through a WLC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "141. Refer to the exhibit. PC-A and PC-B are both in VLAN 60. PC-A is unable to communicate with PC-B. What is the problem?",
    "answers": []
  },
  {
    "question": "142. A network administrator is configuring a WLAN. Why would the administrator use RADIUS servers on the network?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to restrict access to the WLAN by authorized, authenticated users only"
      },
      {
        "answer": "It disables DTP on a non-trunking interface."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The dns-server line is included in the ipv6 dhcp pool section."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The ipv6 nd other-config-flag is entered for the interface that faces the LAN segment."
      },
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 nd other-config-flag"
      },
      {
        "answer": "ipv6 dhcp pool"
      },
      {
        "answer": "to eliminate outsiders scanning for available SSIDs in the area"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "146. Refer to the exhibit. An administrator is attempting to install an IPv6 static route on router R1 to reach the network attached to router R2. After the static route command is entered, connectivity to the network is still failing. What error has been made in the static route configuration?",
    "answers": [{
        "answer" : "The interface is incorrect"
    }]
  },
  {
    "question": "147. What action takes place when a frame entering a switch has a unicast destination MAC address that is not in the MAC address table?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The switch will forward the frame out all ports except the incoming port."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Check the configuration of the exit interface on the new static route."
      },
      {
        "answer": "It enables DAI on specific switch interfaces previously configured with DHCP snooping."
      },
      {
        "answer": "DTP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "151. A network administrator is configuring a WLAN. Why would the administrator apply WPA2 with AES to the WLAN?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to provide privacy and integrity to wireless traffic by using encryption"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "152. Users on a LAN are unable to get to a company web server but are able to get elsewhere. What should be done or checked?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Verify that the static route to the server is present in the routing table."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "153. What IPv6 prefix is designed for link-local communication?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "fe80::/10"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "154. What is the effect of entering the ip dhcp snooping limit rate 6 configuration command on a switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It restricts the number of discovery messages, per second, to be received on the interface."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "155. A network administrator is configuring a WLAN. Why would the administrator change the default DHCP IPv4 addresses on an AP?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "to reduce outsiders intercepting data or accessing the wireless network by using a well-known address range"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "156. What is the effect of entering the ip arp inspection validate src-mac configuration command on a switch?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It checks the source L2 address in the Ethernet header against the sender L2 address in the ARP body."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "157. What protocol or technology is a Cisco proprietary protocol that is automatically enabled on 2960 switches?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "DTP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "158. What address and prefix length is used when configuring an IPv6 default static route?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "::/0"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "159. What are two characteristics of Cisco Express Forwarding (CEF)? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "This is the fastest forwarding mechanism on Cisco routers and multilayer switches."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Packets are forwarded based on information in the FIB and an adjacency table."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "160. Which term describes the role of a Cisco switch in the 802.1X port-based access control?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "authenticator"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "161. Which Cisco solution helps prevent ARP spoofing and ARP poisoning attacks?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Dynamic ARP Inspection"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "162. What is an advantage of PVST+?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "PVST+ optimizes performance on the network through load sharing."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "163. What protocol or technology uses a standby router to assume packet-forwarding responsibility if the active router fails?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "HSRP"
      },
      {
        "answer": "It displays the IP-to-MAC address associations for switch interfaces."
      },
      {
        "answer": "The switch updates the refresh timer for the entry."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "166. A small publishing company has a network design such that when a broadcast is sent on the LAN, 200 devices receive the transmitted broadcast. How can the network administrator reduce the number of devices that receive broadcast traffic?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "Segment the LAN into smaller LANs and route between them.*"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "168. What else is required when configuring an IPv6 static route using a next-hop link-local address?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "interface number and type"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "169. A technician is configuring a wireless network for a small business using a SOHO wireless router. Which two authentication methods are used, if the router is configured with WPA2? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "personal"
      },
      {
        "answer": "enterprise"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "170. Which mitigation technique would prevent rogue servers from providing false IPv6 configuration parameters to clients?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "enabling DHCPv6 Guard"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "171. A PC has sent an RS message to an IPv6 router attached to the same network. Which two pieces of information will the router send to the client? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "prefix length"
      },
      {
        "answer": "prefix"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "172. While attending a conference, participants are using laptops for network connectivity. When a guest speaker attempts to connect to the network, the laptop fails to display any available wireless networks. The access point must be operating in which mode?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "active"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "173. Which three components are combined to form a bridge ID?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "extended system ID"
      },
      {
        "answer": "bridge priority"
      },
      {
        "answer": "MAC address"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "1. What two characteristics describe an FTP connection? (Choose two.)",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "The first connection established is for traffic control and the second connection is created to transfer a file."
      },
      {
        "answer": "Files can be downloaded from or uploaded to the server."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. Refer to the exhibit. Consider the IP address configuration shown from PC1. What is a description of the default gateway address?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It is the IP address of the Router1 interface that connects the PC1 LAN to Router1."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the application layer service being requested from Server0 by PC0?",
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "HTTPS"
        }
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Which statement describes the physical topology for a LAN?",
    "answers": [
      {
        "answer": "It defines how hosts and network devices connect to the LAN."
      }
    ]
  }
]